Samuel Bordo

LinkedIn | Website samuel.t.bordo@gmail.com | 224.330.0309

PROFILE

Recent college graduate (May 2018) with strong creative, analytical and problem-solving skills. A reputation as a dedicated team member and a passionate leader. Significant experience with creating and developing projects both individually and as part of a team. Open-minded with skills in experience/interface design, digital marketing and business strategy. Passion for music, photography, art and outdoor sports, including climbing, hiking, scuba, surfing and skydiving.

EXPERIENCE

PROXFINITY | VISUAL DESIGNER

September 2018 - Present | Chicago, IL

- Developed web content/design using WiX and Javascript.
- Worked with technical team to create experience/interface design that corresponds with Google Material Design.
- Created various print and digital design deliverables using Adobe Suite.

BORDO WEB DESIGN | PARTNER

August 2015 - Present | Evanston, IL

- Developed the capability to design, build, test and deploy functional products.
- Gained experience developing and maintaining client relationships as well as managing a business.
- Learned how to monitor and maintain products.
- Led hands-on training sessions to educate clients on how to utilize their new Wordpress website.

DESIGNS 4 DIGNITY INTERNSHIP | INTERN

January 2014 - May 2014 | Chicago, IL

- Worked with both interior designers and architects to gain holistic understanding in the development of physical design projects.
- Cultivated experience in a non-profit space.
- Spent time working in a professional environment.

PROJECTS

COLLAB | TEAMMATE

January 2016 - May 2016 | St. Paul, MN

- Collaborated with college-facilitated incubator team to develop a mobile app that connects students for study sessions in real time.
- Worked on developing a product with a focus on front-end user interface development and market research efforts.
- Produced business deliverables after assessing market readiness through market research.
- Improved presentation skills by delivering multiple business pitches to mock investors.

EDUCATION

MACALESTER COLLEGE | B.A. IN ECONOMICS

St. Paul, MN | GPA: 3.0

- Completed relevant coursework in micro and macroeconomic theory, core concepts of computer science and business/product development.
- Spent 2017 spring semester abroad in Queensland, Australia at James Cook University in Townsville.
- Participated as a four-year NCAA athlete as a wide receiver on the Macalester varsity football team.
- Researched and authored a Behavioral Economics study on gender and competitiveness.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

DESIGN SOFTWARE

Comfortable:

Figma • Sketch • Adobe Suite

PROGRAMMING

Some Experience:
Python • Java • HTML • CSS

SOCIAL MEDIA

Unsplash.com: 3 million+ account views